RIDHO FEBRIANSA

Software Engineer

Profile

Experienced Software Engineer who delivered enterprise projects, such as Omnichannel, Fish Warehousing, School System, and Cosmetic Retail Infrastructure. Skilled in NextJS, Chakra UI, NodeJS, TypeScript, and PostgreSQL for Frontend and Backend. An active contributor and volunteer at national tech community.

Experience

Product Manager, Zero One Group - Indonesia

January 2023 - July 2023

- Handle an enterprise client to build a whole infrastructure to solve scaling and deployment issues
- Manage team infrastructure engineer in sprint for 6 months to solve problems and deliver solution to client
- Investigate and solve migration issues during maintenance time and during rush hour
- Able to reduce deployment time from 20 minutes to 10-15 minutes
- Able to run autoscaling with Magento framework

Product Engineer, Zero One Group - Indonesia

March 2022 - December 2023

- Build omnichannel project using Fastify and React.js and deliver it to client by holding a training and knowledge transfer session.
- Lead backend engineering team in Fish Warehousing project by using Fastify and Test Driven Development process.
- Be a speaker in internal session to share my own perspective to be a good product engineer with good product domain knowledge and a good product ownership.

Junior Developer, SIESTA - Bandung, Indonesia

March 2021 - March 2022

- Build backend and frontend for end-to-end school and university system management using Express.js and Next.js.
- Rapid development requires a lot of detail attention and task to remember which part should be fixed while new feature is being developed

Web Developer, Nanas Media - Surabaya, Indonesia

August 2020 - December 2020

- Build canva-like app using Express.js, VueJS and MongoDB for backend and frontend.
- Mocha and Chai were also used to make sure that frontend behavior is consistent among development.
- Build canva-like feature on top of HTML canvas by modifying SVG, it is unexpectedly not easy due to lack of documentation.

Education

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Information System, Surabaya University - Surabaya

August 2016 - February 2021

- Build LINE Chatbot using PHP as a holiday project to help students automate status checking process on the new enrollment system
- Offered a freelance by lecturer to help School of Business to have their own Entrepreneur Management System, hired 2 more students and built using Laravel and Flutter.

Contacts

Indonesia ridho@fbrns.co https://fbrns.co

Skills

NextJS

Chakra UI

Tailwind

Fastify

Express JS

PostgreSQL

Languages

Indonesian - Native

English - Intermediate

Japanese - Beginner

• Build Library Management System using Flask as a thesis to recommend popular book genres to librarian,

≅ Projects

Covid-19 Indonesia Hub, Personal - https://github.com/ridhof/covid19hub

- When pandemic hit RRC at first, people didn't believe if its exist. Building such hub are done by many community and countries, which I aspire the most is Tokyo Metropolitan.
- Following their idea, I built a simple version which includes daily cases and news contains covid.
- Data were scrapped from Indonesian government and local news website using NodeJS scrapper.
- Backend were using Vercel style to deploy server side API
- Frontend were using VueJS

Bookmark, Personal - https://github.com/ridhof/bookmark

August 2023

- Bookmark is a web application for Bookmark Management, developed using NextJS and Chakra UI
- Bookmark goal is to able to easily manage bookmarks across devices, including collaborate and sharing bookmark to anyone

Volunteering

Speaker - Fasten Mobile Development using Angular and Nebular, Developer Circle Surabaya

September 2019

Event and Web Volunteer of PyCon ID, Python Indonesia

2019, 2021, 2023

Speaker - Day-to-day as a Product Manager and what to prepare to be one, Google Developer Student Club Universitas Hasanuddin

March 2023